Welcome in to Bears Weekly powered by
IGS Energy. A Chicago Bears Network
production. Bears Weekly is brought to
you by Advocate Healthcare, Athletico
Physical Therapy, CDW, Conniey's Pizza,
IGS Energy, and Menor Light. Here are
your hosts, Jeff Chiliak, aka the mayor
of Bearsville, and his sidekick, Tom the
Surf Master. Well, welcome to spring
everybody and another week of the Bears
building towards the 2026 season. It's
intriguing to be sure what is being
cooked up at Hall. We'll discuss tonight
on Bears Weekly here on ESPN 1000 and
the Chicago Bears radio network with
Super Bowl winning Bears guard Tom the
former Bears quarterback Jim Miller. I'm
Jeff Jonia, Dan Barilli, Jordan Treup,
Katie Fox, our producers with Kender
Smith producing in the ESPN 1000 studios
tonight. The executive producer of the
Bears radio network is Eric Estroski.
Coming up on the program, Tom and I had
a chance to visit with assistant GM Jeff
King on the Bears, etc. podcast, episode
213. Wherever you get your podcast,
check it out. We'll run some of that and
our interview with new Bear safety Kobe
Bryant. Fellas, good evening. Hope
everybody's well. And yeah, happy
spring. Spring tomorrow, Tom. What do we
call that?
>> Spring equinox. Yes, spring. You know,
each each day is continuously getting
longer by another minute. Hopefully we
start some nice weather along with it
because I don't remember this late into
spring where we're getting uh you know
inches of snow and you think of what
they had up in Green Bay and Door County
where they had the one of the largest
single day snows storms ever 26 in. So
>> yeah, they deserve it.
>> Look, there you go. Looking forward to
SP. But you know, one thing about this
spring that I really enjoy is we know a
lot more about the coaching staff and we
know a lot more what's the requirement
of the coaching staff is. We know a lot
more about Ben Johnson and his
requirements that he states at the
podium and how they carry through the
practice field. What every position
coach is capable and willing to do to
make sure their positions are are more
well prepared. So, um, as as many guys
have they been bring been been able to
bring in and how they're getting ready
for the draft still at this point, I'm
most excited about the coaching staff
than anything else.
>> Yeah, I think they've elaborated on on
what they're going to get. We're going
to hear from obviously from from Jeff
King the type of players that they're
targeting. So, I think we'll get to
know, you know, like about Kobe Bryant,
about Cam Lewis, you know, do they fill
the roles of what the the coaches and
and the general managers believe they
they can fill? We know they want to get
speedier uh on a defense. You've talked
a lot about, Jeff, uh the versatility of
what players can provide. Can they do
more than say just a safety position?
Can they play corner? Can they be do can
they do other things? because they've
swapped out a lot of players,
specifically the the safety position
that I know is going to be critical
moving forward when you move on from
from Brisker and obviously what uh Kevin
Bard uh brought to the table and now
you've got a couple of new safeties and
we'll we'll see if it's going to be a
totally different look and how they're
going to rock and roll and and do a lot
more things uh defensively say at that
one specific position.
>> Jim, I I I talked to Press Taylor this
past week. We'll hear that interview
coming up next week. The Bears new
offensive coordinator and and the one
thing that really stuck with me and
really sticks with him is how Ben is
uber urgent right now. Well, you got to
believe there's just a lot more that
what Ben Johnson wants to do
offensively. You know, we we know
specifically last year with Caleb
Williams, it's his new it's a a new
system for him. It's basically, if you
remember, Ben Johnson said, "Throw
whatever you learned in the trash."
We're we're starting over from from
ground zero. So, they're they're still
in their infancy stages. They did more
underneath the center with Caleb
Williams. He's going to be able to do so
much more offensively, not to mention
young players like Loveland and Burden
and all these young players that are
going to be able to to do uh a lot more.
So, I agree. You know, there there's the
best is yet to come. I I think that's
what you got to say about the Bears
offense. is still in the infancy stages.
>> All right, some changes on the roster,
Tommy, but some uh old faces back with
the Bears. A couple new ones as well
over the course of the week. Uh the
roster at 68 now. Uh the additions, Jack
Samborn, the Lake Zurich product back on
the Bears after a year in Dallas. Injury
plagued a year ago, but uh they
certainly know what they're getting,
Tom, in a player like this, not only
just as a linebacker, but on special
teams as well. You know, he's going to
give his full effort 100% of the time.
and uh a big rockam sackum linebacker to
hit you.
>> Yeah, he's a perfect fit into this
locker room. You know what to expect out
of Jack Sanborn on a daily basis. He's
mentally and physically prepared and if
he stay stays healthy, he's going to ba
be a great contributor. He can play
every single position and he can play
every single position that's asked of
him on special teams. He's in on a lot
of tackles. I know he was a fan
favorite. You know, I flu took him down
to to Dallas for a reason. I saw, you
know, unfortunately he goes down with a
groin, but he was averaging six tackles
a game and as Tom mentioned, has a lot
of flexibility, has played every
position at linebacker, and he seems to
always be around the football. So,
what's not to like about Jack Samborn?
>> And Jaylen Jones back on another
one-year contract. A valuable special
teams player living on the edge, you
know, like a lot of these guys do a
series of one-year contracts in their
career. And then James Lynch, Tommy,
comes aboard. last two years with the
Titans, but we're familiar with him from
Minnesota where he was a fourth round
pick. People might not know this, but at
Baylor, he had 23 career sacks and was a
Big 12 defensive player of the year, but
that's another defensive lineman added,
I believe, now 13 defensive lineman, uh,
Tommy, on the roster.
>> Yeah, but you know, the thing about
Lynch is he can play a variety of spots.
He can play everywhere from outside
defensive end and any technique you want
to call it to the inside techniques that
are required by Dennis Allen in this
defensive line. And I think when you
have a guy like that that's that
maneuverable, it gives you a lot of
different types of packages that he can
be included in, you can go anywhere from
a three, four, and fiveman defensive
line because of his versatility and his
width and his length. So, um I think
he's going to be an exciting part uh in
in upgrade the competition.
>> Jim, what's your familiarity with Lynch?
>> Yeah, I think well, like you said, when
he was in college, very productive
player. Yeah, he obviously knows the
division uh being in Minnesota, but I
think he's a rotational guy that I think
we know last year the Bears didn't stop
the run well, plus the pass rush. He can
provide some interior pass rush and it's
going to be ultra competitive as you
mentioned, 13 guys. So, I think that's
one thing. You know, you look at last
year when when Ben Johnson came on
board, remember there were no depth
charts. You know, there were no depth
charts. I think there's no depth charts
either. Certainly, some players have
solidified themselves, but guys up
front, they're going to have to prove
themselves and there's going to be an
ultra competition at the defensive line
position moving forward this year.
>> Yeah, I took a gander at this, but as I
saw it the other day, and I'm always
reminded uh that the 85 Bears were the
youngest team in the league when they
won the Super Bowl. So was the Seattle
Seahawks this past season. The youngest
team by by an edge. Uh Green Bay still
at near the top of the youngest team. So
and the Bears are like middle of the
pack as is as it roster stands now with
68 players. Uh but I'm going to go down
the list here. So among the 13 defensive
linemen, Tommy, only Grady Jared is over
30. He'll be 33 next month. Contavious
Street and Montes will be 30 by the
season opener. And interesting, you got
an eight-year player like Devin Bush who
is turning 28 only in July and uh
Edward's an eight-year player as well.
No DBs will be in their age 30 season.
Jaylen Johnson and Cam Lewis, the new
addition from Buffalo, each entering
their seven seasons. We'll get to the
offense in a minute, but uh you want to
have some experience, but you want to
lean into the youth for that speed and
that athleticism, that agility that
Dennis Allen speaks, Tommy.
>> Yeah. And you know, listen, you got some
leaders like Grady and TJ and Kobe and
Jaylen that are all team leaders,
position leaders. And even though
they're young guys, they got a lot of
valuable experience that they'll be able
to talk about inside the locker room and
on the practice field
>> with Jim Miller and Tom the I'm Jeff
Jonia. Coming up next, assistant GM of
the Bears, Jeff King. This is ESPN 1000
of the Bears Radio Network.
>> Welcome back to Bears Weekly on the
Bears Radio Network. Here's your host,
the voice of the Bears, Jeff Jonian.
>> This segment of Bears Weekly is brought
to you by IGS Energy with Tom and Jim.
Jeff Jonia had a chance to sit down this
past week with the former NFL tight end,
a fifthrounder in 2006, 5 years with the
Carolina Panthers, three with the
Arizona Cardinals to scouting intern
with the Bears in 2015. Along the way,
seven promotions later, and after two
years as senior director of player
personnel, the Bears assistant general
manager, this is our interview with Jeff
King, beginning his 12th season with the
Bears organization.
>> I I think I said it earlier. I I I
appreciate the ability to see it from
the ground up. Um, you know, coming from
the player side, um, you know, you have
some idea of what goes on, how the
sausage is made, but having the
opportunity to do some of those jobs at
the bottom and, uh, work my way up, I
think it gives me a little bit of
appreciation not only for the jobs that
those guys do, but um, you know, a lot
of, uh, learned skills throughout that
process that, um, I think are important.
But you know, Jeff, from the time that
you were playing tight end, growing up
through college and into into the pros
to where that position has grown its
role to, is there any other position
that you find that has a bigger
expansion of duties than the tight end
position? Um, I'd say probably like
safeties now. Um, just in the way that,
you know, defensive coordinators can
deploy them as nickels or dimes. you
know, a lot of the high-end safeties
have a do a multiple roles. Um, so kind
of tight end safety, um, you know, their
role their their their role and the way
that they're deployed has kind of
changed and morphed over the years and
kind of it's tied to each other, right?
Um, you know, with all the different
ways that that old coord offensive
coordinators can deploy a tight end, you
know, defense have had to kind of change
the way they they attack that as well.
So, um, you know, I think as as the game
has changed and become more open, um,
and now it's coming like an accordion,
like the way that we play offense,
right? Like it's it's very, uh,
condensed at times and then we can open
it up and, uh, expand those guys' roles
on the perimeter as well. So, um, I
think the back end in terms of the
safeties and the tight ends have
probably grown the most in my opinion.
>> Is there a one, two, three and how you
scout those guys? that this is their
first requirement. Then they got to do
this as well and then they also have to
somehow contribute this. Is there a one
two three role when you're um exploring
those types of positions?
>> Yeah, we'll start with the tight end. I
mean for us um you know the duality of
the role is important for us, right? I
mean, Coulson obviously gets the
acclaimed um and the accolades as a
receiver, but I thought he blocked
pretty well at the point of attack last
year. And and that's a um that's an
important piece for us um you know, to
keep us balanced, to keep um the way
that Ben wants to play offense uh with
the two tight ends in the game. So, um,
obviously we appreciate Coulson's
ability to separate, that's what he
hangs his hat on, but, um, his ability
to hold his own in the run game, and I
think he's only going to get better
there. Um, you know, he's going to have
a first first time full off season with
us, um, to get a little bit stronger.
Um, and then, you know, the way that
that he plays, his play demeanor, um, I
think is very important. I think he
plays the game the right way. he plays a
physical brand of football at the point
of attack uh even though that he may be
outweighed at times or um versus versus
bigger opponents on the edge. But um
first it starts there the duality of it
um and then once you get from there um
then it's about okay how how can we fit
him into roles of the offense that
accentuate his skill set and obviously
that's where the receiving chops come
into play there. Um, on the safety side,
um, you know, obviously we've made a
big, uh, emphasis this offseason with
play speed, um, play temperament. Um, I
think Kobe Bryant's probably the
biggest, uh, emphasis of that, the
biggest example of that of like, you
know, we want guys flying around down to
the football. Uh, we want guys playing
passing lanes. Um, uh, instincts is a
big part of that, but play speed, play
temp, um, physicality, um, is also a big
play there. So, um, that's where I would
start there.
>> There's so many different aspects of
this job after you hung up the pads and
helmet. Uh, what have you, in your
opinion, had to learn the most uh to
rise as you have in this organization
and in this sport? Um, yeah, I think the
details of of being organized and and
staying um one step ahead in terms of
your duties, I think that's important of
of how you go about your your day, your
week, your season. Um, whichever phase
you're in, um, you know, whether it be
pro scouting, um, you know, UFAS to to
college scouting and then the draft. So,
there's an element of of organization
that I think I had to learn. Um, and
then from the scouting side, I think
Tom, you could probably speak to this
too, but there are biases you have as a
player. Um, there's certain things that
you believe in, um, that you may have to
change a little bit, um, of how you view
it, uh, as an evaluator. Um, and some of
it's the way the games changed. Um, some
it's the way that colleges are now
developing or are not developing players
just because of NAL or um the way that
they practice or the way the offenses of
or the spread offense um especially the
O line. So um there are some things like
that you have as a player that you
believe in that you may have to change
the way you think about it holistically.
Do you have to be stubborn a little bit
too uh in that in
>> I wouldn't say stubborn.
>> Stubborn. And are you a good salesman?
>> Well, I I think you have to stay
convicted. Um I think that's the most
important thing as a scout is um you
know, you watch the tape and then you
stay convicted in in in what you believe
in. Um I think that's the biggest thing.
Um because once you become wishy-washy
or go back and forth and and then now
even in this role like you don't know
how to read scouts if they're back and
forth. Um I I think the scouts that say
that stay convicted in what they believe
in and are consistent how they grade
players for the most part um you kind of
know what they feel and and why they
felt that way. Um not to say you agree
with it, but you know where they stand
and how they saw the player. So I think
that helps in the in the end game. Does
it help you and did it help you to scout
because you did what these guys you're
scouting did at a high level college and
the NFL?
>> For sure.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I I think um knowing the game I
mean that's part of knowing the game um
the nuances
um you know I think when you see things
that uh you know are hard um and guys
are accomplishing it or um you know the
little things that you appreciated as a
player that you see in other players um
it just g it just gives you a little bit
more insight of into the player. Okay,
this guy has to be detailed because I
know this isn't easy. Um, I know this I
love this player because he plays the
game the right way. He plays the game
the way that I would appreciate as a
teammate. Um, those things I think stay
stay important even even on this side.
when you go and you fill some voids in
free agency, does it make you rethink um
what you need out of the NFL draft or
are they two separate entities or does
one change what the other one is if you
have uh some big time hits in the free
agency market like you guys have had?
>> Yeah, I think I think we start here. Um
we'll start with free agency is is just
first let's get impact players, right?
Um I think that's where it starts. um
you know, let's say Kobe Kobe Bryant for
an example, you get an impact player um
and then you start to fill in um some
tags of of guys that can fill roles for
you. Um and then if you hit on a couple
of those guys um and and now you're
start to build a roster in the the goal
being to be able to still pick freely um
with a best player available mindset. I
don't think that we're going to get away
from that. I think if you look at even
last year, um, you know, it it's not
common to pick a tight end in the top
10, right? Um, but based on how we felt
about Coloulston and and his his ability
to impact us and the and how he felt
where he fell in that draft, we took the
best football player um in that draft
for us. And so, um, it really had
nothing to do and the draft wasn't
really tied to free agency in that way,
but um, you know, we wanted to become
faster, more aggressive, uh, as a
football team. Um, and I think we we
tried to accomplish that in free agency
and then we'll head into the draft with
a best player available mindset with
still those characteristics in mind.
>> That was a part of our Bears etc
podcast. Check it out on all the Bears
different platforms or wherever you get
your podcast. Episode number 213. Great
conversation, Jim. Dip in here because
he gave some outline of what they're
looking for without being specific, but
you you get into the mindset of a scout
and he appreciates the journey of of
what he went through, but also all these
guys out on the field away from their
families for an entirety of the year to
uh scour and find the right guys that
are eventually going to become Bears.
>> Yeah. Well, first he talked about the
emphasis on speed, you know, and he
specifically brought up uh Kobe Bryant,
how his speed is really going to impact
the Bears of the team. I I thought Tom
asked him a really interesting question
about, you know, how he had to get out
of his biases as as a player. And now
when you're in the front office and
you're scouting players, there is a
bigger picture. There's kind of the the
micro when you look at a player to to
player and then there's the macro and
how it affects your your whole team. And
it sounds like he's into the macro now
of how every player fits. And he talked
about specific players and then he
talked about, you know, specific players
meaning your impactful free agents and
draft picks. And then he talks
specifically about the role players, you
know, because it it is certainly you
want the best football player, but we we
always talk about the 53man roster.
Yeah, you may have a 53man roster of
impactful players, but are they the
right players? Those 53 players may not
be the right role players. You know,
specifically, you brought up uh Jaylen,
you know, think of his special teams
impact, what he specifically brings to a
team as a role player. And that is a key
component of it when you're looking at
the right 53 players rather than just 53
great football players. They got to be
the right 53.
>> Keen eye for talent, knows what he
wants, and is open about what he wants.
So, uh, there's a great set of eyes and
instincts, uh, for scouting players with
Jeff King, now assistant general manager
as his duties expand up at Halis Hall.
All right, when we come back, more
discussion about the Bears offense. This
is ESPN 1000 of the Bears Radio Network.
>> Bears,
>> it is gone.
>> Bears weekly.
>> Time expires.
>> A deep dive into all things Bears
>> and the Bears win. with Jeff Jonia and
Tom Fair. This is the home of the Bears,
ESPN Chicago.
>> This segment of Bears Weekly is brought
to you by Athletico Physical Therapy.
Visit athletico.com to request an in
clinic or virtual appointment and start
feeling better tomorrow with Tom Bayer
and Jim Miller. Jeff Joniac. We looked
at the defense and the uh experience
level. Tom, offensive line Joe Tuni will
turn 34 during this season. Gare
Bradberry will be 31 in June. everybody
else on the uh short side of 30. So
that's uh a good blend of experience
there. And you know, whatever Joe's
accomplished in his career, which has
been a bunch, I just can't help but uh
think that whatever this guy has been a
part of, they've all won. I don't
believe he's ever had a losing season in
his career.
>> Yeah. When you talk about Joe being, you
know, close to 34, he understands how to
take care of himself during the off off
season. I think that's some of the most
important things that a veteran needs to
know and learn. They have to have that
routine in the off season that gets them
mentally and physically prepared for the
season they're getting ready to embark
on. And Joe probably has as much
experience in that than anybody inside
that building. And a lot of times that's
stuff that he can share with some of the
young guys. So, uh, Garrett and Joe I
think are two important parts of this
offensive line. And um I expect the
offensive line to continue to have the
success that they had this past year.
And I repeating myself, I think a lot of
it has to do with Dan Roshar, the
offensive line coach, and his staff
because he knows how to prepare these
guys. Unless you're a Garrett or you're
a Joe Tuni that they're going to play
the positions and and Jonah Jackson,
they have these guys play a variety of
positions during training camp in case
that scenario presents itself where they
got to move around. And we saw what Joe
did in the last game of the year
>> at quarterback. Of course, Case Keenum,
38 years old. Khalif Fayman enters his
ninth season. He'll turn 32 in camp. But
everybody else at the skill position and
in the backfield. Jim Miller all under
30. So a younger offense around a young
quarterback.
>> Yeah, certainly. And I think with a lot
of room to grow with those young
players. Obviously for for Raymond kind
of swap him out with Duivere. Obviously
he'll double as a return man as well.
It's a player that Ben Johnson knows
well, but I'm excited about the the
young playmakers at the skill position.
You know, even Jade Walker, you know,
his impact late in the year with that
big touchdown catch. Luther Burton's
going to continue to grow. Roma Doomsday
hasn't reached his height. So, these are
a lot of young players that I think
we're we're going to see start to go
into their prime. And that's the same
with the tight end position. Lovelin
seems to be, you know, look at his
impact as, you know, a first round draft
pick of the Chicago Bears. And for the
the backfield, obviously, Manungai, he
had an impact. He's a young player who's
going to continue uh to grow. So,
there's a lot of what I should I say
tentacles of where these players are
going to end up. kind of their their
seeds were planted last year and we'll
see what they grow into cuz they already
showed flashes and glimpses of of great
things and you'd like to think that
those are going to grow and sprout and
and be playmakers on a more consistent
basis. So, a lot of young talent there
and we'll see where it goes. Jim, I I
touched on this in some of our other
shows and maybe here right on this show,
but I I want to emphasize again and from
your perspective as you playing the
quarterback position, you go in as a
young quarterback and you know, you
experienced a lot of change in your
career, but Caleb's now got the same
same people in the room minus Declan
Doyle, but Press Taylor was there last
year. Maybe didn't have as many
interactions with Caleb, but he was a
passing game coordinator. But you're
also bringing back Case Keenum who had a
big impact on Caleb from what we
understand that experience. He speaks
the truth. He told us that last week. He
does not sugarcoat anything from his
eyes, from his perspective of being a
veteran NFL quarterback now at 38 years
old. And Tyson Bean back as well to
learn as well. Everything is same around
him. It's going to be not everything
being the same in terms of the the the
the way they run the offense, but it'll
be similar and layered with more
learning. How important is that for him?
>> Yeah, it's going to be huge. Just think
about how more advanced they're going to
be. I mean, it was a struggle for for
Caleb Williams, but now it's like we
always said, he's already crossed that
that bridge, you know, so he's so much
far advanced with players that he's
worked with, players that he knows, an
offense that he understands, and they're
going to be able to do a lot more cuz
they've already they've already crossed
and done the early stages of what it
takes to to run this offense. So, it's
now going to be more advanced. It's
going to be more accelerated because
they know what's expected of them and
there is going to be more put on their
plate of what they're going to be able
to do because they've earned that
responsibility and they want to get
better as well and they want to do more
as an offense so that they're more uh
difficult to defend. And I think as a
player you're excited, you know it's a a
challenge and that you know the reasons
why you have the answers now, you know,
to the test. uh so to speak and so
you're able to do more and play with it
a little bit more and they'll be more
advanced as an offense.
>> So put yourself in the shoes of Case
Keenum. Now you're a backup quarterback
on a football team. How do you know when
to insert yourself? How do you know when
to give advice? How do you know to be
point counterpoint quarterback from the
Case Keenum roll? if a a practice is is
lulling or it's not a a good practice,
he'll be able to insert himself kind of
challenge uh Caleb Williams and I think
Caleb's going to be up to the challenge
to respond to that. I remember even
myself, you know, backing up uh Tom
Brady in certain practices where maybe
he's a little frustrated with how things
are going and say, "Hey, man, you got to
remind you're in charge, man. You're
you're you're the one in control of it
all." And that it is true cuz you're the
one that has the ball in your hands that
you can change things really with what
you say in the huddle, how you address
things, maybe how you pick things up,
the intensity of the practice. Say when
Tom Brady used to challenge uh the
defense in a goal line period. So you're
in control of a lot that really can have
a huge impact on your team because again
I always say that about the position.
It's a leadership position by default.
So Caleb is going to have much more of a
platform when maybe he was the young
player, you know, and not much was
expected with veterans like DJ Moore and
Keenan Allen around him where really
that's not the case now. This is his
offense. He's in charge of it and he is
the elder statement other than say Joe
Tuni that is really the the mouthpiece
for the offense. So Caleb's going to be
in control of a lot of it and I think uh
a guy like Case Keenan will will
challenge him to assert himself in doing
so.
>> All right, coming up next, our interview
with Kobe Bryant, the Bears new safety.
It's coming up here on ESPN 1000 or the
Bears radio network.
>> Bears Weekly is back and so are Tom and
Jeff Jonia on ESPN Chicago.
This segment of Bears Weekly is brought
to you by IGS Energy. One of many
interviews we're going to be rolling out
here in the weeks leading up to the NFL
draft and the start of the offseason
program. Kobe Bryant sat down for a
conversation when he arrived in Chicago
last week for the start of the free
agent period. The veteran safety who
started his career as a cornerback out
of the University of Cincinnati. Very
high on what the Bears have planned for
him and what this team offers. your
skill set. Obviously, we know it, we
watched it, we watched you in the Super
Bowl. How do you see it fitting here in
this scheme?
>> Yeah, I see it I see it fitting pretty
well, obviously. Um, you know, just
being a leader. Um, you know, obviously
in takeaways and, uh, you know, being a
consistent tackler, you know, just being
being a leader back there as well, too.
So, I feel like I'm fit really well
here.
>> Yeah, that 25 Bears team set a standard
for taking the ball away. I like how you
say you jump right in there and your
numbers say so as well. Is that just an
instinctual trait that you have uh that
you're a heatsicking missile to the
ball?
>> Yeah, absolutely. Uh that's just
something that my my dad and my older
brother, you know, kind of, you know,
prep me for just growing up, you know,
that's something just to play with
urgency, get the ball, and you know,
ultimately just have fun. It's football,
you know, just treat it like you're in
the backyard again and just like I said,
just keep having fun out there.
>> Not many gentlemen are in this uh
building that won a Super Bowl. So,
congratulations on that.
>> Thank you. Um, and that championship
mindset is something that develops. Of
course, you come in with it in the NFL,
you think that way, but then it's really
hard to get there. What could you share
about that experience and mindset that
you need to have to be a champion?
>> Yeah, takes a lot of hard work. Um,
definitely going to deal with adversity,
but that's part of it. That's part of
life and football. But just consistently
getting better each and every week, you
know, and um, just staying together,
honestly. And, uh, like I keep just
saying, have fun together.
It's a long season and uh you know
health is wealth as well too. So just
take care of your body and like I said
just having that mindset from OTAAS all
the way up to the end of the season.
>> I think uh players genuinely will uh be
attracted to a champion uh in the locker
room because you can speak to the
journey.
>> Um are you okay taking that on and be
that leader in the locker room?
>> Absolutely. I I I fully embrace you know
being a leader. Not being someone I'm
not but just being who I am. you know,
that's kind of the mindset that I've had
that I've had since I've stepped into
the league. Um, and you know, just I'm
open arms always, honestly, you know,
and vice versa. You know, I'll ask
questions as well, too. So, I'm excited
to be here and help others as well, too.
>> Uh, what excites you most about working
with Ben Johnson and the the culture
that you may have seen or heard after
this uh great first year for Ben?
>> He's just scratching the surface,
honestly. Um, you know, he's a young
guy, very smart from what I've, you
know, seen and heard as well too. and
you know just to be a part of this
organization you know bunch of great
guys around here and I'm very excited to
be a part of it
>> and you said coaches are getting younger
I guess
>> yeah they are they are
>> you just left you left one right what
kind of impression did Mike Levine
>> yeah uh coach Mike is a great guy
honestly you know I tons of respect and
very thankful for him and believing in
me um you know he's a he's a very smart
guy as well too and you know I know I
can always count on him and vice versa
so just you know I said tons of flowers
to him and much respect
>> all right so with Dennis Allen what he's
trying to build here as well. Uh he
loves speed number one. Loves taking the
ball away as well. The physical. He
loves versatility. Do you feel you check
all those boxes for coach Allen?
>> Absolutely. You know, I wouldn't be here
if I didn't, you know, fit the boxes and
um you know, I met with him early today
and we're both excited to, you know,
play together and work together and, you
know, it's going to be a great year.
>> One of the most impressive coaches that
I've seen come along in recent years is
coach Al Harris in the secondary. So,
and you're grinning, so you already
know.
That's a that's a great player himself.
You know, the thing about coach Harris,
he's undrafted. He was cut, he was
traded, he became an allp pro,
>> he's won a lot of games, and now he's an
excellent coach and he's really
developed a lot of players. Uh, I'm sure
you know the history of him. And what
will that be like for you to have a
coach like that?
>> Very exciting. The first person I seen
and I just smiled and we both smiled at
each other. So, I we're we're going to
have a great, you know, great career
together. you know, he he gives guys
interceptions, which we which everyone
loves. So, you know, I know a lot of
guys that he's worked with, you know,
end up seven plus 10 plus interceptions.
So, I'm very excited, you know, so I
can't stop smiling, you know, but I'm
excited.
>> What is your game day personality like
from warm-ups to the finish?
>> Absolutely. I'm pretty locked in, but
I'm calm, poised, but you know, I
definitely agree. The secondary, um, you
know, we we definitely take leadership,
you know, not just on the defense, but
on the team as well, too. You know, I
feel like we bring a lot of swagger, um,
energy, you know, competitive nature,
you know, all those things, we bring it
into the team. And I'm very excited to
work with, you know, the guys in the
room.
>> Top down. I know you played corner also,
right? So, safety position, you played
all over the place. uh what is that top-
down mentality like for you in terms of
understanding what is now a very
complicated era of football if you ask
me the constant motion right
>> I mean it's a shell game in many
respects but
>> has that led you to understanding
>> uh that you have to get deeper into that
tablet or the game plans being thrown at
you
>> most definitely um you know offensive
corners are getting smarter um you know
the game is definitely not getting
easier guys they're getting faster. But,
uh, ultimately just being who we are,
who who's got us here, and staying in
the playbook, ask questions, you know,
and continue to improve even when we're
having the success that we're going to
have. Just continuously work and keep
getting better.
>> Got a message for Bears fans?
>> Yeah, I'm excited to be here. Thankful
to be here, honestly. And, um, you know,
it's going to be a great year. Just mark
my words. So, now
>> I know you've been number eight for the
great Kobe Bryant. Named after, you
know, Kyro Santos, currently the kicker.
Is there going to be a discussion? Oh,
uh, I definitely might, you know, reach
out and, you know, see about the number
eight. So, we'll see.
>> All right. Welcome to Chicago. Thank you
so much for your time.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Delightful guy who is going to be put in
a a different position. He's coming in
with leadership expectations as a
veteran who's won a Super Bowl,
>> you know, and I'm glad that he doesn't
shy away from that. You brought it up a
couple times and he is willing to accept
the leadership role. I like that he puts
a priority on his tackling skill because
that's one of the most important things
that defensive players and defensive
backs do. And then he talks about being
a part of a championship team and how
that resonates with them still and how
he's comfortable with talking about that
in the locker room. And then he says
health is wealth. And I think that's
really a good phrase that needs to be
repeated by a bunch of young guys that
making sure that you take care of
yourself so you can live up to the
expectations and the physicality of the
game that keeps you on the field. So
everything that he's said in meetings is
super encouraging to me. Very active uh
player. Obviously had an impact getting
turnovers. Obviously the the Bears love
that. Tom mentioned the the tackles.
Look at the tackles for losses. So, this
is a very active player. I think we know
in Mike McDonald's system defensively,
their guys are very versatile, much like
Dennis Allen wants him to be. And here,
the Bears swap out their their safeties.
And he's had the ability to play both
safety and corner uh that we mentioned
kind of the more you can do. So, he'll
be used in a various ways, I think, by
Dennis Allen to have an impact for the
Bears. I think both him and Cam, they're
going to they're going to have a lot of
rock and roll safeties that they're
going to be interchangeable that they're
up at the line of scrimmage and both
asked to do a lot of things in coverage
and to to rush the quarterback and be an
in the box player as well. They'll be
interchangeable like that for Chicago.
>> And I would venture to say that there
very well could be a rookie, a high
higher round draft pick potentially that
could be battling for a starting job in
that back end of the defense. and uh
Larry Mayer from Chicago Bears.com wrote
an article on uh everybody's uh
projection at pick 25 for the Bears. I'm
going to run down the list. It's an
interesting collection. Charles Davis of
NFL.com, Texas Tech defensive tackle Lee
Hunter. Jim, we saw him at the Senior
Bowl. Very vicious off the line of
scrimmage. But the Toledo safety Emanuel
McNeel Warren, a big tall 6'4 rockam
sackum guy is not afraid of contact uh
out of a program that's producing NFL
caliber defensive backs was chosen by
several people including Daniel Jeremiah
and also from Lance Zerine from NFL.com
as a potential pick 25 for the Bears in
the secondary. Heard a lot of great
things about this kid. I I can't wait to
dig in a little more and watch his tape,
Jim.
>> Yeah, but 6'4 right away. That's uh
that's a different body for him. That's
kind of like Kyle Hamilton, say of of
Baltimore. When you look at a guy that
big and it's it's very rare, obviously
uh for the Bears, they're very familiar
with a young player who just left who
played great at at 6'4 at the the
quarterback uh position, but it's just a
very rare body type. You know, for
Seattle, they had Tariq Woolen who was
well over 6'4 and he ran in the 43
range. But, uh, you know, that's kind of
the Legion of Boom territory when you're
looking at guys of that body size. And
that's why I would compare him to to
more Cal Hamilton of the Baltimore
Ravens. That's a a big frame.
>> You know, one thing I'm surprised about
at all the mock drafts, and I've looked
at 10 or 11 of them, and every one of
them has a defensive player aside from
Monroe Breing. One person thought that
that offensive tackle would slide down
to the Bears. And if he did, I guess it
you'd have to investigate him because he
is a big, tall, talented offensive
tackle. But it seems the consensus is
the Bears from defensive tackle to
outside pass rusher to defensive back.
It's a defensive player.
>> Yeah. Couple corners in there as well.
Uh, this was interesting and I forgotten
this, but Bears have not used a top 50
pick on an edge rusher since Leonard
Floyd ninth in 2016. How about that?
We'll break after this. Tom's thoughts
coming up. Maybe he can dwell on that
when we return here on ESPN 1000 on the
Bears Radio Network.
>> Welcome back to Bears Weekly, a Chicago
Bears production on the flagship home of
the Bears, ESPN Chicago.
This segment of Bears Weekly brought to
you by Athletico Physical Therapy. Visit
athletico.com to request an in clinic or
virtual appointment and start feeling
better tomorrow. Time for Tom's
thoughts. Tom, you got me confused on
this week's quarterback O line still our
flotation device,
>> right? The heck. Oh, if you look at if
you look at the positions of strength
and knowledge and what they've been able
to accomplish last year, the question
was where is Caleb going to go and Ben
Johnson, what's going to happen with the
offensive line? We saw what the
offensive line became and we saw what
Caleb ended up the season as. I think
when you look at the development of the
defensive backfield, uncertainty at the
linebacker pos position, the variety of
defensive linemen you're going to play,
I do think the quarterback and the
offensive line are going to be the two
stabilizers of your football team until
they get all the other positions uh and
personnel decided. Um, and I do think
it's the quarterback and the offensive
line. I know there's questions at the
left tackle position, but I still think
they're the most stable positions the
Bears have.
>> Yeah, I think well, if you look that
this was a top 10 offense a season ago.
So, I think if they are able to, you
know, minimum stay the same or take a
step forward, which I think we all
predict that they will, that's going to
give the the defense time to gel. You
know, last year I talked about, you
know, it probably is going to take eight
or nine weeks for the Bears offense to
catch fire. the defense was kind of the
the veteran side of it that kind of held
on and got all those turnovers and gave
the offense more opportunities. But this
year, I think it's the opposite. I think
the the Bears offense will be, you know,
time of possession. They're much further
along. they'll be able to to let the
defense kind of settle in and let them
gel with all the potentially what we
think is going to be a defensive-minded
draft and all the free agents that the
Bears brought in to help their mid20s
ranked defense. So, I do I think the
offense can carry the defense till they
catch on fire and start playing uh you
know hopefully at a at a top 10 rate.
>> Good, better, best. Tom
>> Kyle Manungai, he's got to stay as good
as he's been. And I think that we didn't
know what Kyle was going to be able to,
you know, add to this offense until we
saw him about three or four games into
the season. When you talk about better
Luther Burton, they got rid of DJ Moore.
We didn't know what he was going to be
until he recovered from his injury and
then he started to be included in the
game planning and then we say, "Wow,
this guy has got capabilities of being
really good." But he can be better and I
think that he's going to be offered more
to be better. And then the best Coulson
Lovelin. Here's a guy that came up with
some of the best numbers from the tight
end position on the Bears or around the
league. And so he has the ability to be
the best and he's another guy that came
in with injury uncertainties. So when
you look at good, better, best and you
look at where Kyle was drafted, Luther's
slow start to injury and Lovelin was
coming off of shoulder injury. So I
think we got good, better, best in all
those guys
>> and I think all those players earned it.
You know here when you go out and you
perform like Manungai when he started to
have the impact he earned more
responsibility. I'd say the same with
Lovelin and obviously with the injury to
to Roma Dunay that gave Burton some
opportunities to to get in there and all
those players earned more opportunities.
Now with where they are, they're going
to be further along, advanced, and and
developed, and I would like to think
that they're going to earn more
opportunities as well. Now, whether
Lovelin leads the team in receptions
again, we'll see. Only he'll be the one
to decide that. But I got to believe
Burden's going to say, "Yeah, let me
take some of that responsibility off
you." Cuz I think I've earned more
opportunities to get some footballs
thrown my way. So, I think the players
are are going to be the ones to decide
it. And a guy we haven't really been
talking about much, but uh you know, you
can't forget him. He's a top 10 pick.
Roma Dunay. I've seen videos of him
working in the weight room, so he's
getting strong. All right. New ground
zero has got to begin at the midway
point. Is that right? What? What?
>> Well, so this is what this is what my
point about it is because at the end of
the season, Ben Johnson says, "We're
going right back to ground zero." But
ground zero after you've been on a
coaching staff for a little while is a
little different. The quarterbacks are
going to be familiar with the rhythm of
their cadence and the players are going
to be familiar with the rhythm of the
cadence. They're going to be familiar
with the motions that are expected out
of Ben in this offense. You're going to
understand the landmarks and some of the
route directions that Ben is going to go
out there and creatively continue to
design. So, ground zero is like the very
first day that you go on the practice
field with a new coach that nobody knows
nothing about anything. There's a little
certain elements to football that you
know just like on the defensive side of
it, you know the different personnel
groupings, you know the variety of
personnel positionings that Dennis Allen
will use. So when we're see in training
camp when they're out there with six
defensive backs, it's not going to catch
us by surprise because we saw it towards
the end of the season. So, what I'm
saying is ground zero to me, and I'm not
putting words in anybody else's mouth,
ground zero is something that there's a
certain portion of it that's already
been installed that's going to be
reinstalled. So, ground zero to me is
there are some factors that go involved
get involved.
>> Yeah. I I just think it's going to be at
such a more accelerated rate, you know,
with what they're their ability to what
they're going to be able to install is
just players their their depth of
knowledge is is so much further along
that again the you know when they're
installing the playbook like you said
the base offense I think they already
know they're they're more advanced now
they're moving on to uh to more indepth
things that they're you know they just
be much further along and be able to get
more you deeper into the playbook
because just their their gravity and
their knowledge of offense and where the
coach is coming from is just so much
further advanced.
>> All right, boys. Nicely done. We have to
go. The executive producer of the Bears
Radio Network, Eric Estroski, thanks
Kendra Smith in the ESPN studios. That's
going to do it for us. This has been
Bears Weekly on ESPN Chicago, home of
the Chicago Bears. Coming up next, Amber
and Ian for just a half hour before
White Sox spring training baseball. Have
a good night everybody.
>> Thank you for listening to the Chicago
Bears Network presentation of Bears
Weekly hosted by the mayor of
Bearsville, Jeff Jodiac and Surf Master
Tom the podcasts are available on the
Chicago Bears official app brought to
you by Verizon and Apple Podcast. Bears
Weekly has been brought to you by Miller
Lightite.